Eliane Fortes - Software Developer

Melbourne – Australia • 0405 097 837

<u>elimrfortes@gmail.com</u> • <u>linkedin.com/in/eliane-fortes</u> • <u>github.com/elifortes</u>



PROFILE

Passionate Software Developer with a comprehensive foundation in full-stack development, gained from Le Wagon's Web Development bootcamp, and a strong background in business analysis and customer service. Skilled in creating customer-centric solutions using technologies like JavaScript, React, Node.js, and Ruby on Rails, complemented by practical experience in HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, and database management (SQL/NoSQL). My previous roles as a Support Worker and Business Analyst have honed my problem-solving, analytical, and organizational skills, ensuring a user-focused approach to software development. With projects ranging from an Airbnb-inspired boat rental platform to a group-gifting web app, I have demonstrated my ability to innovate and execute within collaborative environments. Graduated in Business Administration and furthered my analytical skills through a Data Analytics course at General Assembly, I am driven to apply my diverse skill set and fresh perspectives to contribute to a forward-thinking software development.

My skills include:

- JavaScript- Ruby on Rails- Ruby on Rails- Bootstrap- React.js- Node.js- Express.js- SQL/NoSQL

- GitHub - Heroku - Customer Service

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Support Worker at **Discover Nursing Australia**, Sydney (Jan 2018 – Aug 2023)

- Provided exceptional customer service, emphasizing empathy, and understanding.
- Addressed and resolved client queries effectively, indicating strong problem-solving skills and customer-focused service.
- Coordinated care consultations, reflecting excellent organizational and time-management abilities.

Business Analyst at Valeo Thermal Bus Systems, Caxias do Sul/Brazil (Jun 2016 – Sep 2017)

- Conducted regular statistical report generation, emphasizing analytical skills and attention to detail.
- Analysis and negotiation of orders and delivery schedules with customers.
- Responsible for monitoring daily revenue and meeting targets.
- Participation in the qualification of processes, identifying and applying innovations and differentiated solutions, and validating the applicability of new technologies, knowledge, and practices.

EDUCATION

Web Developer Bootcamp | Le Wagon, Melbourne

Oct 2023 – Dec 2023

- Completed a 9-week full-time intensive coding bootcamp.
- Applied practical knowledge of HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, GitHub, Heroku and Ruby on Rails.
- Developed and Airbnb-inspired boat rental platform.
- Proposed and developed the web app 'Gift Genius', completing the project within 2 weeks as part of a 3-person team.

Data Analytics Bootcamp | General Assembly, Sydney

Apr 2022 - Jul 2022

- Applied practical knowledge of Tableau, PostgreSQL, and Excel.
- Delivered a project analysing Chicago City Council phone requests and provide a detailed examination of complaints by the councilperson elected to represent the area.

Business and Management Administration Degree | UCS, Caxias do Sul

Mar 2010 – Jul 2017